Guide to the Stanford Album Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
The Stanford Album photographs
1906-1989
PC0075
Stanford University
1 Linear feet
This collection pertains to the photographic sources used in the production of THE STANFORD ALBUM (Margo Davis and Roxanne Nilan, Stanford University Press, 1989). The materials are arranged in three series: copy prints, alumni sources, and negatives. The first series contains copy prints of many of the images in the final book; they are arranged by page number. The second series consists of copy prints and negatives of photographs that were loaned by alumni to the authors, but not used in the book; (images that were used are included in the copy print series). Also included are a few original prints and negatives and several accompanying letters. This series is arranged alphabetically by name. The third series consists of negatives of many of the images in the final book; these are arranged by page number.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The images from alumni sources were loaned for use in THE STANFORD ALBUM; any other use will require permission from the individual alumni.
Description of the Collection
This collection pertains to the photographic sources used in the production of THE STANFORD ALBUM (Margo Davis and Roxanne Nilan, Stanford University Press, 1989). The materials are arranged in three series: copy prints, alumni sources, and negatives. The first series contains copy prints of many of the images in the final book; they are arranged by page number. The second series consists of copy prints and negatives of photographs that were loaned by alumni to the authors, but not used in the book; (images that were used are included in the copy print series). Also included are a few original prints and negatives and several accompanying letters. This series is arranged alphabetically by name. The third series consists of negatives of many of the images in the final book; these are arranged by page number.
Access Terms
Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Copy prints
  - Unnumbered pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Illuminated S; A040 - two women in boat
  - Pages 1- 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    p. 1 JLS daguerreotype; p. 3 LS Jr's notebook; "Horse in Motion" plate; p. 6 left upper & middle photos; right lower photo; p. 7 all
    Brock, Bobbe Harris; Harper, Tro.; Ludlam, Jim; McCarty, Jeannette Hill; Zeppenfeld, Mary Lou Andreatta
  - Pages 18-27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    p. 18 "snow in Mayfield" (right middle photo); p. 18 saloon (upper right photo); p. 27 LS Jr on his pony (upper left photo)
  - Pages 32-39 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    p. 32 lower photo; p. 35 lower photo (GP 14737); p. 36 upper photo (possibly from SUA glass negs?); p. 38 lower right photo; p. 39 roads at oval (from A041)
  - Pages 42-59 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    p. 42 Botanical Club (from glass negs); p. 45 Stanford postcard; p. 53 upper image (prossibly from glass negs); p. 55 all photos (from A040 and A044); p. 59 two lower photos (from A027)
  - Pages 64-75 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    p. 64 top photo (from A091); p. 65 top photo (from A036); p. 74 upper left photo (from A027); p. 75 lower left (from A047)
  - Pages 86-88 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    p. 86 upper photo (Crandall album 1904); p. 87 upper right photo (from A044); p. 88 all except upper middle (from A037 and A040)
  - Pages 90-91 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    p. 90 all (from glass negs and A037); p. 91 all (from A011, A042, A047)
  - Pages 97-114 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    p. 97 lower photo (from glass negs); p. 98 upper photo (from A028); p. 100 upper photo (from A041); p. 114 upper right photo (from Hoover Institution)
  - Pages 123-129 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    p. 123 upper photo (unknown source); p. 124 upper photo (Lane Medical archives); p. 129 upper left photo (from SC 533)
  - Pages 130-132 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    p. 130 lower right photo (from A011); p. 131 upper left photo; p. 131 upper right photo (from A046); p. 132 upper right and lower left (from SC 533); p. 132 upper left photo (from A011)
    Rehm, Francis Edward
  - Pages 136-144 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    p. 136 lower photo (from A027); p. 138 all (from Crandall albums); p. 144 top photo (from A011)
  - Pages 146-154 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    p. 146 top and bottom photos (from A048 and Crandall album); p. 148 lower photo (from Crandall album); p. 154 middle photo (from Crandall album)
  - Pages 170-171, 184 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    p. 170 top left and bottom photos (from Hoover Archives); p. 171 bottom photo (from Hoover Archives)
  - Pages 206-210 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    p. 206-07 (from Sch. of Earth Sciences); p. 210 lower photo (from Hoover Archives)
  - Pages 212-214 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    p. 212 all (from Lane Medical Archives); p. 213 all (from Lane Medical Archives); p. 214 top photo (from Hoover Archives)
  - Pages 218-222 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    p. 218; p. 220; p. 222 lower photo
    Harper, Tro.; Ludlam, Jim; McCarty, Jeannette Hill
  - Pages 227-229 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    p. 227 all; p. 229 upper and lower right photos
    Harper, Tro.; Ludlam, Jim; Maino, Jeannette Gould
  - Pages 230-234 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    p. 230 three upper photos; p. 233 upper and middle photos; p. 234 upper right photo
    Cahn, John Phillip; Callvert, Ronald S; Cross, Ira "Red"; Davis, Joseph H.; Harper, Tro.; Marple, Charles Dalliba; Rosin, Stanley
  - Pages 240-241 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    p. 240 all; p. 241 all
    Ludlam, Jim; McCarty, Jeannette Hill; Reuland, Caroline Haddock; Spencer, Richard
  - Pages 243-251 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    p. 243 top photo; p. 245 top right photo; p. 248 bottom photo; p. 251 upper right and bottom photos
    Crandall, David L.; Harper, Tro.; Ludlam, Jim; Lyon, Richards
  - Pages 255-260 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    p. 255 bottom photo; p. 259 top and bottom right photos; p. 260 top photo
    Bustard, John Warren; Harper, Tro.
  - Pages 261-263 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    p. 261 all; p. 263 lower photo
    Harper, Tro.
  - Pages 267-269 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    p. 267 all; p. 268 all; p. 269 all
    Rosebrook, Lois Williams; Zeppenfeld, Mary Lou Andreatta
  - Pages 270-279 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    p. 270 all; p. 275 upper right and left photos; p. 277 left upper and lower photos; p. 279 lower photo
    Hodgdon, Frank W.; Hyer, Bill; Shrader, Judy Wood; Zeppenfeld, Mary Lou Andreatta
  - Pages 280-281 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    p. 280 all; p. 281 all
    Eggleston, Dana Fore; Rosebrook, Lois Williams; Wert., Ann; Zeppenfeld, Mary Lou Andreatta
  - Pages 284-286 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    p. 284 all; p. 286 all
    Crandall, David L.; Hyer, Bill; Sanchez, Margaret Tuttle.
  - Pages 287-288 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    p. 287 right upper and lower photos; p. 288 top and middle left photos
  - Unused images - copy prints and negatives (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Students posed at a fence, ca. 1900 (Hoover Institution album); Students Rice and Cotton in the Quad, ca. 1895 (from A047); Male student in boat, ca. 1910 (from A046)
- Alumni Sources
  - Atkinson/Rehm, 1913-1915 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Skull and Snakes 1913 (2 images); Bonfire 1914 (2 images); Big Game scoreboard 1914; Coach Husky; Senior Crew on Junior Day 1915; Crew team [1914]
    Rehm, Francis Edward (?)
  - Bustard, circa 1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Two men on horseback on campus
    Bustard, John Warren
  - Brock, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Two students on steps of fraternity (OAX); Woman and man outside Roble by cars; Frat men goofing off in the kitchen (OAX); Woman outside Roble
    Brock, Bobbe Harris
  - Cahn, class of 1939, circa 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Group of students outside a dorm
    Cahn, John Phillip
  - Callvert, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Students in car on campus road; Students in convertible behind Quad building or Encina
    Callvert, Ronald S
  - Chuck, Frank, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 5.1)
    Residents of Chinese Clubhouse; Frank Chuck (2 images); Group photo of 22nd Conference Chinese Student Association of West Coast at Stanford University, Aug. 13-16, 1924; Group photo of 23nd Conference Chinese Student Association of West Coast at Stanford University, 1925
  - Crandall, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Group of students sitting on picnic table
    Crandall, David L.
  - Gould/Bartlett, 1906-1934 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Era Chamberlin in dorm room, 1909; Stanford library after quake, with students in buggy, 1906; Memorial Arch after quake, 1906; Memorial Church after quake, with two women standing on broken wall, 1906; Era Chamberlin, Mabel Bartlett, Claudia Clark and others in dorm room, 1908; "Dragon" from senior circus, 1907; 9 women students at Kings Mountain, 1907; Frenchmen's Tower, 1934; Masque Ball election, April 18, 1934
    Gould, Mabel Bartlett
  - Hodgdon, 1947-1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Frank Hodgdon & Bobbe Lipp at graduation, 1948; Theta Chi group, Russell fireside, 1947 or 1948; Letter from Frank W. Hodgdon III, Feb. 2, 1988
    Hodgdon, Frank W.
  - Hyer, William, prints, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Students on campus; Beta Theta Pi house; Hoover Tower; Views from Hoover Tower; Old Union
  - Hyer, William, negatives, 1943-44 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Several Chappie images
  - Hyer, William, negatives, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    "The Gondoliers"; Gaieties; Several Ram's Head production; Sadie Hawkins's Day; Scrum, 1943 Quad; Several coed images
  - Hyer, William, negatives, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Hoover Tower and views from; Inner Quad view; Saving History Corner tree 1943
  - Hyer, William, negatives, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Bailey Willis (used in S. D. 5/6/43); Mrs. Frances Neilson (used in S.D. 2/25/43); Belgian items from Hoover (used in S.D. 1943); Col. Harry Allen with ROTC horse, circa 1944
  - Ludlam, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    4 students on campus; Janet; Harle Garth; Jean Fox
    Ludlam, Jim
  - Kambara, class of 1937, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Backfield of "Vowing Sophs" - Buck Van Dellen, Bobby Grayson, Frank Alistiza (?), Bones Hamilton, 1935; Japanese Student Club, on steps of club house, 1935
    Kambara, George Kiyoshi
  - Lyon, class of 1938 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Hank Luisetti during a ball game
    Lyon, Richards
  - Maino, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    The Row, 1934, Sigma Phi house on right; Lucile Salter Packard on roof of Delta Gamma house, 1931 or 1934; Lucile Packard and Zoe Ann Hill on roof of Delta Gamma house, 1931 or 1934; Edna Bonn Russel on Roble Hall roof, 1931; Roble Hall roof garden, 1931; Members of Delta Gamma on front steps of house, 1934 (2 copies)
    Maino, Jeannette Gould
  - Marple, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Medical School in S.F.; Alpha Kappa Kappa costume party, 1938
    Marple, Charles Dalliba
  - McCarty, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Collapse of the boathouse [no negative]; 3 women sunbathing [no negative]; 2 women sunbathing [no negative]; Lake Lagunita event - canoe with "Trot with the Tots" sign & women in nurse's uniform [no negative]
    McCarty, Jeannette Hill
  - Reuland, class of 1934 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Miss Doyle, director of Roble
    Reuland, Caroline Haddock
  - Ricci, class of 1936, circa 1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    6 women on grounds of Lagunita Court - Joyce Dunkerl, Ruth Aynesworth, Esther Pecton, Margaret Lazzarone, Mary Craig, Doris Burke; Letter from Margaret Lazzarone (Mrs. Don Ricci), n.d.
    Ricci, Margaret Lazzarone
  - Rosebrook, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Students at the Boathouse; Woman and serviceman in the Quad; Students at Rossoti's (Alpine Inn); Women on steps of dorm (Lagunita Court ?); Woman at the Boathouse; Two women on campus
    Rosebrook, Lois Williams
  - Rosin, class of 1932, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Encina Hall, with parked cars; Woman sitting by a lake (probably not Lagunita); Interior of dorm (Toyon ?); Pillars in Toyon ?; Student in cap & gown with two women
    Rosin, Stanley
  - Sanchez, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Group of women by Quad gate; Campus road with puddle; Art shot of iron fence somewhere on Quad; Letter from Margaret T. Sanchez, 5 Mar. 1988
    Sanchez, Margaret Tuttle.
  - Shrader, circa 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    "Selling war bond" - group of men and women on tank outside Bank of America (2 copies)
    Shrader, Judy Wood
  - Spencer, class of 1939, circa 1939 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Woman by Quad pillar
    Spencer, Richard
  - Tomblin, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Two women outside Roble, 1943 - Erlda Leaf and Marilous Sutter; Letter from Marilou Sutter Tomblin, n.d.
    Tomblin, Marilou Sutter
  - Wert, circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Students in a car; Letter from Ann Wert, Feb. 11, 1988
    Wert., Ann
  - Zeppenfeld, circa 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Women sunbathing (on roof or porch); 5 women outside a house on campus
    Zeppenfeld, Mary Lou Andreatta
- Negatives
  - Contents page - group of students (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Preface - 2 women in boat (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Page 1 - JLS daguerreotype (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Page 1 - JLS daguerreotype (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Page 1 - LS daguerreotype (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Page 6 - lower right: two women in stadium (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Page 6 - middle left: man and woman with cars in background (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Brock
  - Page 6 - upper left: 3 men on a wall (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Ludlam
  - Page 39 - roads at oval (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Page 55 - top left: dorm interior (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Page 55 - middle left: dorm interior (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Page 55 - bottom left: dorm interior (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Page 55 - upper right: dorm interior (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Page 55 - lower right: dorm interior (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Page 59 - lower left: 4 women in P.A. room (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Page 59 - lower right: 4 women with bikes (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Page 64 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Page 64 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Page 65 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Page 74 - upper left (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Page 75 - lower left (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Page 86 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Page 87 - top right (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Page 88 - upper left: 2 women in top hats (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Page 88 - lower left (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Page 88 - center: students on Gov. Stanford locomotive (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Page 88 - middle right: 2 students in clown costumes (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Page 88 - lower right photo: group of students in costume (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Page 90 - lower left (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Page 90 - lower right (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Page 91 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Page 91 - middle left (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Page 91 - middle right (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Page 91 - lower photo (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Page 98 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Page 100 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Page 129 - upper left (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Page 130 - lower right (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Page 131 - upper left (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Page 131 - upper right (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Page 132 - upper left (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Page 132 - bottom left (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Page 132 - upper right (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Page 136 - bottom photo (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Page 138 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Page 138 - middle photo (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Page 138 - bottom photo (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Page 144 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Page 146 - top photo (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Page 146 - bottom photo (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Page 148 - bottom photo (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Page 154 - middle photo (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Page 170 - upper left photo (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - page 170 - lower photo (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Page 171 - lower photo (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Page 184 - upper left (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Page 184 - upper right (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Page 199 - bottom photo (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Page 204 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Page 222 - bottom photo (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Page 227 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Page 229 - upper photo (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Page 229 - lower left (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Page 230 - upper photo (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Page 230 - middle left (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Page 230 - middle right (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Cross, Ira "Red"
  - Page 233 - upper left (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Page 233 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Page 234 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Davis, Joseph H.
  - Page 241 - upper left (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Page 241 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Page 241 - lower left (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Page 243 - upper photo (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Crandall, David
  - Page 245 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Page 251 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Page 251 - lower photo (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Page 255 - lower photo (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Page 267 - top photo (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Page 267 - lower photo (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Page 269 - top photo (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Page 269 - middle photo (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Page 269 - bottom photo (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Page 270 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Hyer, Bill
  - Page 275 - upper left (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Page 275 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Page 277 - upper left (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Page 277 - lower left (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Page 279 - lower photo (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Hodgdon, Frank
  - Page 280 - upper left (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Page 280 - lower left (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Eggleston, Dana Fore
  - Page 280 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Page 281 - upper left (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Page 281 - lower photo (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Page 281 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Page 284 - upper photo (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Page 284 - lower photo (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Page 286 - right photo (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Page 287 - upper right (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Page 287 - lower right (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Page 288 - upper photo (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Page 288 - lower right (Box 4, Folder 43)